

ERICK TIJERO

Android Developer

ericktijerou@gmail.com

1 +51 960297960

ın	linkedin.com/in/	'erickti	ierc

ericktijerou.com

ABOUT ME

Energetic and curiosity-driven Android developer with 4+ years of experience writing top-quality clean code for high-paced businesses. I learn new stuff every day to be on a top of Android technologies and best practices. I'm working with libraries and tools like: Android X, Android Architecture Components, Koin, Coroutines, Android KTX, and another common libraries.

I'm interested in learning more about Data Science and Artificial Intelligence.

Whom want to look at my code. GO HERE: https://github.com/ericktijerou

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Android Developer

October 2019 - Present

- · Design, build, and maintain high performance, reusable, and reliable Kotlin code.
- · Work with outside data sources and GraphQL APIs.
- · Collaborate with cross-functional teams to define, design, and ship new features.
- Work on bug fixing and improving application performance.
- · Continuously discover, evaluate, and implement new technologies to maximize development efficiency.
- · Translate designs and wireframes into high quality code.
- · Identify and correct bottlenecks and fix bugs.
- Help maintain code quality, organization, and automatization.
- · Unit-test code for robustness, including edge cases, usability, and general reliability.

Technologies used:

Kotlin DSL Firebase CI

App Bundle Dynamic Delivery Coroutines Koin Architecture Components



Senior Android Developer December 2018 - November 2019

- · Translate designs and wireframes into high quality code.
- Design, build, and maintain high performance, reusable, and reliable Kotlin code.
- · Ensure the best possible performance, quality, and responsiveness of the application.
- · Identify and correct bottlenecks and fix bugs.
- · Help maintain code quality, organization, and automatization.
- · Work with outside data sources and APIs.
- · Unit-test code for robustness, including edge cases, usability, and general reliability.
- · Work on bug fixing and improving application performance.
- · Continuously discover, evaluate, and implement new technologies to maximize development efficiency.

Technologies used:

Android Developer

Makeup SDK CI

Coroutines Architecture Components ObjectBox Unit Testing

February 2018 - December 2018

Tekton Labs

- · Unit-test code for robustness, including edge cases, usability, and general reliability.
- · Work on bug fixing and improving application performance.
- · Continuously discover, evaluate, and implement new technologies to maximize development efficiency.

SKILLS & TOOLS

Mobile

Gfi Perú

Android

Kotlin

Java

React Native

Flutter

Frontend

HTML/CSS/HAML/SASS

React

JavaScript

Node.js

Backend

Ruby/Rails

Stefanini

Python/Django

Others

CI Code Review Gitflow Unit Testing

Jupyter Notebook Numpy

Pandas GraphQL API Sketch

EDUCATION

Systems Engineer

Universidad Nacional San Luis Gonzaga

Database Administrator

Universidad Nacional de Ingeniería

2013 - 2014

LANGUAGE

English (Basic)

- · Design and build advanced applications for the Android platform.
- · Collaborate with cross-functional teams to define, design, and ship new features.
- · Work with outside data sources and APIs.

Technologies used:

RxKotlin Clean Architecture ViewModel Room Unit Testing React Native Firebase

Android Developer

October 2017 - January 2018

- · Design and build advanced applications for the Android platform.
- · Collaborate with cross-functional teams to define, design, and ship new features.
- · Work with outside data sources and APIs.
- · Work on bug fixing and improving application performance.
- Continuously discover, evaluate, and implement new technologies to maximize development efficiency.

Technologies used:

RxKotlin Android KTX Dagger Firebase Maps SDK Geofencing Crashlytics

Android Developer

GDC Technology Limited

Solera Mobile

January 2017 - July 2017

- · Translate designs and wireframes into high quality code.
- Design, build, and maintain high performance, reusable, and reliable Java code.
- Ensure the best possible performance, quality, and responsiveness of the application.
- · Identify and correct bottlenecks and fix bugs.
- · Help maintain code quality, organization, and automatization.
- · Work with outside data sources and APIs.
- · Unit-test code for robustness, including edge cases, usability, and general reliability.
- · Work on bug fixing and improving application performance.
- Continuously discover, evaluate, and implement new technologies to maximize development efficiency.

Technologies used:

Java Support Library Retrofit Butter Knife Dagger The Movie Database

Software Developer

devAcademy

February 2016 - January 2017

- Design and build advanced applications for the Android platform.
- · Collaborate with cross-functional teams to define, design, and ship new features.
- · Work with outside data sources and APIs.
- · Unit-test code for robustness, including edge cases, usability, and general reliability.
- Work on bug fixing and improving application performance.
- Continuously discover, evaluate, and implement new technologies to maximize development efficiency.

Technologies used:

Ruby Java Ruby on Rails Android HTML/HAML CSS/SASS

Spanish (Native)

INTERESTS

Cycling

PROJECTS

App FFVV

Facilitate the monitoring of business variables so you can earn more each campaign.

Asesor de belleza

Live makeup cam to try out real cosmetic products. AR makeover styles including lips, eyebrows, hair color, eyeliner, eye color, and lashes tryout in seconds.

Mi Negocio Natura

With Mi Negocio Natura you can place orders and follow them from anywhere, keep up to date with news, watch and share the digital magazine.

Vive BCP

Discover all the benefits you have as a BCP Contributor, download it and start living in the BCP style.

San Pablo

Mobile application San Pablo, book and pay your appointments from anywhere.

GoGas

The APP allows you to buy fuel at the "Repsol" stations with the "GoGas" card at a lower price, you can also recharge your prepaid GoGas card from the APP through the PayMe payment gateway.

Fitadvisor

It is a digital Fit community where people who seek to lead a healthy lifestyle can connect and interact daily.